Hey, you got me up for this.
Yeah, sorry.
Eh, worrying ain't gonna
get 'em back any faster.
We should go after them, man.
They'll be back
when they get back.
Now, just clear your mind.
All right.
They should be back.
They will be.
Hey, Troy promised
to keep Madison safe.
He promised me.
That means something to him.
Does it?
Yeah.
I protected him
when we were little.
You can trust him.
On this, at least.
I'm more worried about the
people who shot us down.
- Jesus, Mom.
- Mike!
- On the road.
- Come on.
You all right?
What the hell happened?
We should talk private.
Talk private?
Did I hear you right?
Coop, Mike, inside.
Let's debrief.
Like hell, Jeremiah.
We all got a right
to hear what went down.
- You're out of line, Vern.
- We got a right to know what happened.
We need to know
how to defend ourselves.
- We gotta know...
- They were Indians.
- They slaughtered them.
- All right, all right.
They slaughtered all of them.
We made it home, huh?
It's nothing we can't handle.
They're dead. They're all dead.
Mike, lock your shit down.
Lock it down.
They're dead.
And we're gonna die, too,
if we don't leave!
- Shut up.
- Is that true?
- If we stay, we...
- Mike, shut the hell up.
If we stay, we die!
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Resynced to WEB-DL by Madridista12</fon
No, no, no, we go after them.
Now. We hit them back.
So you can stroll into another
ambush, Colonel Custer?
There was no way to know.
- No?
- No.
- Did you scout the campsite first?
- Dad.
Huh? Hike the perimeter?
Or did you suffer
some distraction?
Were your already
tasting the blood?
It wasn't Troy's fault.
Oh, you an expert?
No, we... we were cautious.
Ah. Well, let's extend
the caution now.
We're not attacking.
We're right to hold off,
but Walker's not going away.
He's weak.
That chickenshit atrocity
he pulled with Phil...
If he's weak, he'll negotiate.
Negotiate?
There's nothing to negotiate.
It's our land or their land.
I mean, we either
stole it or we didn't.
Stole?
Is this their land?
Every acre you tread is owned
and was owned before...
bought, leased,
or stolen in between.
And what about the ranch?
It was sold to my forebears.
And what the hell
does it matter now?
It matters if he doesn't stop.
It matters if your people think
they're on the wrong side.
Hey, this is my business
to manage.
Don't mistake yourself
or your place.
Dad, she's trying to understand.
Walker's a tribal lawyer.
Sued us since forever.
I handled it last couple years.
And we beat him every time.
And what if he comes back
to the door now?
He won't.
You've never seen
the Black Hat Reservation.
- Mm-mm.
- It's a truck stop, motel, and market.
Rocks and asphalt,
liquor and oxy,
drunken, diabetic
welfare cheats.
I feel your liberal judgment.
It's palpable.
- But that's not racism.
- Isn't it?
No. It's truth.
And I'm talking about
before the apocalypse.
Doubt it's improved much since.
You say what you want,
but the man I saw
yesterday was a threat.
He had command.
Yeah? You got a little crush?
We gotta tell people something.
You talk to them.
It's good they start hearing
more from you anyway, Jake.
What do you want me to say?
Just say we got weapons
and walls and wherewithal.
Say all civilizations
are born of violence.
People give me a headache.
Troy should come with me.
He was there, Da...
- Got it?
- Okay. I got it, I got it.
I've got it. Okay.
- Here, take this off.
- Oh, God.
Thank you.
- Here.
- Careful.
Oh, Mom...
Oh, God.
Damn.
She went south.
She knew people in Mexicali.
I'm sorry.
She's strong.
So are you.
Hey!
Hey.
Sorry...
about the people you lost.
I didn't know most of them.
Phil McCarthy was here
since the beginning, but...
he wasn't a good man.
Your mom okay?
Will be.
Your dad?
No. Not really, no.
He's one of the last ones
standing.
And he's feeling that.
Russell lost in the fire,
McCarthy dead now.
Vernon's the only other
Founding Father left.
Just getting picked off
one by one.
Are you afraid?
No.
Border's a violent place,
always has been.
Show me?
Safety.
Semi-auto, like a pistol.
Full auto. Stick with semi.
Don't I need a new target?
Mine'll be the ones
in the bulls-eye.
What happens when your dad goes?
Who takes over the ranch?
Most people here
are libertarians.
They don't take orders
very well.
Tuck the stock
into your shoulder.
Don't tense.
Yeah, but people
look up to your dad.
Yeah, it was his land.
It'll pass to me and Troy
when he dies,
but people look to whoever
they feel is worth looking to.
Could be anybody. Could be you.
Your father wants it to be you.
Why wouldn't it be?
You're right, people are
gonna look to somebody.
And if it's not you...
Breathe out when you
squeeze the trigger.
Come in.
Sorry, Madison, sorry.
I was just looking for Alicia.
She's out and about, Gretchen.
Probably with Jake.
I'll... I'll just...
Is Mike okay?
Freaked.
He said you saved him, though.
He said everybody
would have died without you.
Come in.
It isn't just my brother.
It's my whole family, my father.
Vernon? Sit down.
My dad doesn't think we're safe.
He helped make this place,
and he doesn't think it's safe.
I've never seen him scared,
not even when the dead rose.
- But he is.
- What'd he say?
He said he should have known,
that it would never end,
- that violence begets violence.
- Wait, wait, slow down, slow down.
He said it's just starting.
He wants to go.
He wants to leave the ranch.
I'm scared.
Shh, listen to me.
There's no place safer
than here.
Well, he doesn't believe that.
He knows a colony in Colorado.
Dad says the Rockies will
be safe, at elevation.
Who did he say that to?
Anyone who will listen.
He feels responsible.
He's a founder.
Fire!
Fire! We got fire!
What's happening?
Everybody out!
No, they're everywhere!
They're all over the place!
Son of a bitch.
50 yards from the front gate.
What the hell
was that sentry doing?
How many total?
Militia counts about 20.
All built to die like this one.
It's not meant to burn us out.
They want the land in one piece.
They want us off of it,
like they said.
They don't have the arms
or the balls,
so they do this bullshit.
If Walker was gonna come,
he would have.
But he can't.
Your people are scared,
Jeremiah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What brings you down here?
Uh, lumber?
Drywall screws.
You flying solo?
- What?
- Luciana, she, uh... she take off?
Do me a favor.
Say her name again.
Whoa, whoa, easy, easy, partner.
It's just good you didn't
take off after her.
That's all I'm saying.
Okay?
Whoa, Dax, Dax,
what are you doing?
- Huh?
- Don't start, Troy.
No, this is not a good time
to cut bait, Mrs. Daley.
Feels like the best time.
I have sacrificed too much.
Not gonna wait for them
to finish off my entire family.
They will pay. They will
pay for what they did.
Now, Dax... put the flour back.
I'm sorry Troy.
We've just been thinking...
Thinking? Thinking?
Thinking about stealing
our shit and hauling ass?
Huh?
This is what we put in.
Following the rules here.
Oh, the rules. Right, the rules.
Well, the rules are here for
the members of our community.
You leave, you're not a member.
Take it up with your father.
We spoke this morning.
All right.
Okay.
We should talk.
Um, should we?
I may disappoint.
- Listen, Vernon is...
- Wha...
Headaches still?
Migraines. You get 'em?
Unh-unh. Father did.
The light would start
to hurt him.
- Oh.
- Jeremiah...
What did you wanna say
about Vernon?
- He's...
- Right here.
- Jeremiah, can I get a word?
- Hmm?
Yeah. You're having one.
Uh, in private.
There's nothing you can't say in
front of Madison or anybody else.
Look, we're friends
going on 30 years.
You know I love this place.
I love what we started.
But a man's family comes first.
Just gotta protect them
best he knows how,
and the best I know how
is to leave.
Now.
A little precipitous,
don't you think?
Run off at the first sign
of trouble?
Sign of trouble?
They killed eight of ours.
They sawed Phil's...
Hell, Otto, that could've been...
All right, all right.
All right?
Well, what do you
want me to say?
You don't need my permission.
You wanna go, go.
You don't wanna go
out there, Mr. Trimbol.
My mind's made up.
I'm sorry, Jeremiah.
Mike going with you?
My family's leaving, Troy.
30 years, huh?
He wasn't always like that.
Some men, they have kids,
turns them into women.
He's a founder.
If you can't keep him here,
how you gonna keep
the rest of them?
Well, what would
you have me do, hmm?
Give them a reason
to stay, fight.
Give them a reason?
Aside from the fences
and the militia
and the stores
and this community, huh?
I welcome them onto my land
with open arms,
and now I gotta get down
on my hands and knees
and beg 'em to stay?
There's a fight coming.
Everyone who leaves
leaves us weaker.
To hell with this.
Troy!
Keep that gate closed, Jimmy!
- Your father gave the okay.
- I don't give a damn.
You open that gate
and I shoot you in the head.
Open the door.
- I'm not doing this, Troy.
- Open the door, Vernon.
Mike? Mike, get your
ass out here now.
Come on, get your ass out here.
People died for us, Mike!
Our people,
and you're gonna run, huh?!
- It's not what a man does, Mike!
- Troy. Troy!
Troy, stand down.
Dad said they could leave.
Yeah, he said they could leave,
not with ranch property.
What property? This is theirs.
They gassed up, didn't they?
Gas is ranch property.
And I guarantee you
that they took plenty of shit
from the pantry!
And I want to see
an inventory, Vernon!
- I want it inspected!
- This is not what Dad wants.
Why should I give a damn
what Dad wants?
He never gives a shit about me...
You're not protecting the ranch.
The hell do you know about it?
You haven't a clue
what this ranch is about.
I mean, she's been here
a week, and she gets it.
You gonna fight for what's yours
or you gonna surrender it, huh?
- That's not your call, is it?
- You gonna fight or you gonna surrender?
You're not in charge, are you?
What the hell
is wrong with you, huh?
- No! Hey, Dad, Dad. Dad, Dad.
- No, no! Come on.
Come on.
God damn it.
Looking for something
to take out the old man?
I've been there.
It's the first thing
folks will grab
if there's a run on the place.
Good.
I was worried you might
do something rash.
To my family?
No, no. Never.
Can't blame my worry.
No.
All I've ever had
in my... my whole life
is this... this place and...
these people, and...
I don't know, it just...
I don't understand, you know.
Like, the world out there,
it's, uh...
It's burned.
They wanted to see
for themselves.
Anyone who leaves is dead to me.
Now, Mike, he was...
He was soft, but he was...
He's been my friend
since I was a kid.
He stayed in school
when I got... I got pulled.
But he never quit on me. Never.
Even when others did.
He didn't quit on you, Troy.
He just stood by his family.
He wouldn't look at me.
He just...
Hard to know how to
react to something like that.
You make sure
no one else leaves.
Save them from the same mistake.
I'll help you.
I want you all at attention.
All right. That's a start.
Tracking Mike down and beating
his ass into the ground,
that'd be a start.
No, Mike's gone.
He's not coming back.
That's the end of it.
I don't want to hear
his name again.
From now on, we set an example.
We become a model
of what this place needs...
Order, discipline,
chain of command.
We have to make those
people up there feel safe.
Or they'll leave, all of them.
We have to defend
this ranch with our lives
or they will be slaughtered,
all of them.
This place, this place
is all we have.
And right now,
it is... teetering.
And the only thing
that can save it is us.
Now, I'm not gonna draw
a line on the floor.
I'm not asking
whether you're with me.
You are with me, all of you.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir!
Jeremiah, what are you doing?
This is where it goes,
right here.
Where the hell
have you been, huh?
I've been drinking here
all night, alone.
Here.
No, thanks.
Come on. You?
Especially me. I'm high on life.
I like that.
Hey, slow down.
- Slow down.
- Mm.
Ah.
What happened to your hand?
Oh... you know that song,
"Can't be with the one you love,
love the one you're with"?
Well, that goes the same...
with hitting people.
I don't mind.
The hand...
distracts from the headaches.
Well, listen, man,
tomorrow's another day,
a better day,
'cause you're gonna be
too hung over
to get in any fights.
So why don't
you just crash here?
This is a scared spot, you know.
Me and Vern and Russell
and McCarthy,
we sat here one night and...
conceived the movement.
My life's work.
Now two are dead and...
one is dead to me.
God damn it, man.
Jeremiah, no, no, no, hey!
I'm s... I'm sorry.
Your home. Your gun.
There's blood in it.
It's in the earth.
Bible study?
Jake's.
Jake?
It's nothing serious.
The rhythm method is bullshit.
I told you that, right?
Yes, when I was 13.
I thought you were
talking about a band.
There's birth control
in the pantry.
I'm sorry, it's just the
stakes are so much higher now.
You like him?
Like, yeah.
I'm not in love.
Been in love. This isn't it.
It can creep up on you.
Jake's important to us.
And I like him.
In that order?
Does there have to be an order?
Oh, God damn.
It's bright.
Good morning.
So, I raided the pantry.
Turns out "It's for
Otto" goes a long way.
No, thanks.
About last night...
Last night I was
at the bunkhouse
with my mom and Alicia.
Why, did I miss anything?
How long has that been there?
Is it one of ours?
It's Vern's.
- Go get your mother.
- Why?
Just go get your mother.
That's a baby.
They could have let it out.
It's a long way to go.
Two horses, a lot of feed,
lot of water.
They'd have slaughtered it.
They'd have killed it
if it were like that.
Treat the hide.
Cure the meat.
They wouldn't just free it.
So it escaped.
They're dead.
I know it.
It's just a question
of how they got that way.
Be ready for that.
"Black Hat Reservation"?
I'm going to Walker.
I'm gonna work this out.
I've known him for years.
I know Black Hat.
- You need a map to get there?
- No.
I'm going off-grid. Back way.
It'll take longer,
but it's safer.
- Safer from Walker.
- Safer from my father in case
he sends Troy to stop me.
He should stop you.
He killed your people.
He killed Travis.
He wasn't trying to kill Travis.
No, he was trying to kill you.
Yeah, good people die
easy as bad.
- What does that even mean?
- It's what I'm trying to stop.
More people will die.
You're right, I... I have to be
more than just a voice
in my father's ear.
I meant for you to step up
inside the camp, Jake,
not to go out
on some suicide mission.
I'm the only one
that can do this.
I've dealt with him.
I've settled with him.
- I've beaten him.
- When there were courts!
When there was rule of law!
Walker's not crazy.
He's just fighting
for his people who need him,
people who always
got a raw deal.
Jake, I'm asking you not to go.
Stay ready.
Lots of dead wander
around out here.
Vernon?
Kathy, too.
Mike.
You gonna shoot?
You all right?
She's Alicia's age.
Yeah.
He thinks it was Troy.
No, I don't think so.
Don't think so
or you don't want to?
Even for Troy, this is...
We know Walker was close.
I've seen what he's done.
Indians, right?
Took everything?
Took the helicopter?
- Even took your shoes?
- Yeah.
Would they leave this?
Horses? The RV?
There's a week's worth of
food and supplies in there.
All the things he's done...
never anything like this.
Not to his own people.
Can't be absolutely sure.
I don't think of him as a man.
My boys, they go away
a couple days,
they come to mind.
It's like they're seven,
eight years old again.
I don't know what to do.
We have to go back.
Now.
Troy!
What happened to them?
I'm sorry.
They were good people.
They didn't deserve this end.
Our family, we... we weren't
prepared like you.
We were strangers,
but you took us in.
We've come to love it here.
I wish... my husband
had lived to see it.
But he was killed.
Travis was killed.
He was killed by the same
people who killed Phil
and our people at the outpost.
The same people...
Walker's people...
have now killed our friends...
Vernon, Kathy, Mike...
- Gretchen.
- This is crazy, dude.
I've seen firsthand
how Walker treats his victims.
I saw it at the outpost,
and I just now saw it again.
You built this place together.
Because of that, you've
been safe and sheltered.
You haven't been out in the world.
We have.
I'm telling you,
there's nothing out there.
If you leave, you'll die.
Walker's people aren't strong
enough to force us off this land.
They're trying to scare us.
That's how they want us to go...
A family or two at a time,
out there alone
where nobody can see,
where our militia
can't protect us.
We cannot let ourselves
be fractured.
There are more of us.
We're better armed.
If we stay here together,
we live.
Yes. Yeah.
That was impressive as all hell.
It was necessary.
How do you tell a lie that
big and sleep at night?
How do you do that?
What I said was true.
None of these folks
will die, not tonight,
not tomorrow,
maybe not for a long time.
You and Alicia are safe.
I'll sleep like a baby.
Say it was Troy.
It was.
No one would believe us.
They're more afraid of what's out
there than anything he could do.
You should've told me first
before you did this.
You would've said no.
No. I get it.
I hate it, I get it.
I would have backed you
like I'm backing you now.
Just don't forget what he is.
I didn't go out there
to do that, I swear.
I...
He owed me.
He had to look me
directly in the eye.
He had to say it to my face, say it
like Vernon said it to my father.
He owed me that.
He didn't want
to do that, did he?
He said some things, and...
I did some things.
Then it went bad.
Not what you want
to hear, is it?
You could run this place, Troy,
but not if you let things
break like that.
Last night you had command.
I saw that.
Your militia saw that,
and they responded.
Your brother doesn't have
what you have.
He's not of this place.
You're the survivor.
You're the heir.
So, no, the last thing
I want to hear
is how you lost control.
That can't happen.
I don't care how you did it.
I don't care why you did it.
All I care about
is that you can control it.
There's a fight coming,
and you have to save us.
Can you?
Yes, ma'am.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Resynced to WEB-DL by Madridista12</fon